Hi again everyone.
So, this is going to be a presentation
of my pic grip.
Uh this is something that I kind of came
up with.
I don't know necessarily if it was
necessary, but um
when I had first gotten my Draco and I
had put some kind of rear adapter on the
side, I had issues with
the grip coming loose. Like it would
like literally just ride off. Um
and I think it might have been a QC
issue. Um but regardless, I got that
like fixed and milled everything. Um
and this is like been 2 years in the
making. You wouldn't expect that, I
know, but
um
it's evidently it's mostly just like for
my personal use and then over time I
learned that people thought it was cool.
Um
as you're probably aware, um
it's kind of bare
um rear. There's no inserts or anything.
That's like a quarter inch of steel here
that you have to Dremel through. It's
very difficult. Um
plenty of videos to show you how
difficult it is.
>> [snorts]
>> Um
this was just more of a simplistic
solution to just number one having a
comfortable grip that fits in your
hands. Um
I'm going to have the images obviously
on my website, but you can kind of see
here it's a lot thicker profile than say
this one.
Feels much better in the hands. Um
especially if you have like
not small hands, but like regular size
hands. I guess if you have bigger hands,
probably we're going to want to get your
own like a Magpul or something cuz those
are really chunky, but this is perfect
for like
I don't know the average built person.
Um
it goes on just like my 70 adapter where
there's the plate on the bottom. Um so
we're just going to start by unscrewing
the Draco here.
Fully before you can that, let's just
assemble this.
Thumb on the screw plate, and then just
remove it all the way.
Okay.
Literally just going to take
your
little thing here.
Uh there's that little space, little
hole. Just line it up with this little
uh
screw attachment here.
Um
just press into place.
It'll slide right on.
You're going to notice
a little bit of an air gap um on here.
No more than
I can't even be any more than half a
millimeter. Um but you'll see it. Um
that is because this is made of TPU, and
this is made out of PETG, and then these
uh side panels here are also made out of
TPU. Um
there's two screws running down the
middle to kind of like help keep it
reinforced.
That little gap is just the screws
um
flexing a little bit on the
the grip, like on the where they meet.
When you tighten this fully, as we're
going to do right here, that space
disappears. Um
it just kind of gives you some
I don't want to say drop capacity, cuz
like it's safe to drop this, but like it
just removes some of the stress by not
having everything be so tight together.
Um
when I was doing drop testing and
everything, I found that
it it seemed to take
the cosmetic damage significantly better
when there was that little little gap in
there. Um
so that's what that is.
>> [clears throat]
>> Okay, tighten. Don't over tighten, but
tighten.
Um you can guys see the gap's gone now.
I'm going to go ahead and get this
centered again.
I have no idea where my other
Where is this?
All right, it's nice and tight.
And there you go.
You have a monolithic grip-dash
adapter.
Um [snorts]
I suggest using
regular M-LOK or regular pic mounts with
like the M35 screws. Um but anything
that uses a pic rail this should work.
The only thing that you're going to have
a problem with is anything that has like
those wide mouth um that kind of like
wrap arounds that need like those flush
pic rails probably not going to exactly
seat. I did give you
this little portion here where I give
you a larger mouth to like get it on
there, but
anything like large
um in profile
it's not going to stay on.
Um
Just
just throwing it out there like a
warning because um again, when I do drop
testing cuz I test all of the things
that I make
I found that it was putting premature
It didn't nothing broke, but it was
putting a lot of like premature wear
where like I didn't like it. Um
So, I made it to where it's always
It's designed to where whatever you put
on there is supposed to be sturdy. Um
I guess is the best way I can say that.
You you to see kind of like what that
looks like,
Okay.
this is my personal one that I have. I
just took it off for the sake of this
presentation. Um, but I have my pic grip
here.
So, you can see it's the mounts, and
then I have my little folding stock or
brace.
>> [snorts]
>> Um, now mine's made out of PETG fully,
um,
but that's just because
if I like the way this feels weight-wise
much better. Um, but I can't sell this
because it literally breaks if you drop
it too hard. So, um, yours will be good.
I had to make sure it was solid
material, but, um, I can just print
another one for myself. So, that's why
mine's made out of PETG fully.
>> [snorts]
>> Um,
but yeah, that's literally it.
Uh, if you guys have any questions, of
course, let me know. Um,
yeah. I'm actually relatively happy with
how this came out. I don't know if I'm
going to do any iterations, but, uh,
yeah, that's it.
Thanks.